

# Nick Rossolatos

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### PROFILE

24-year old full stackdeveloper from Greece with3+ years of work experiencein web development.

#### CONTACT

+30 6976703479 nikos@panelsensor.com

#### SKILLS

 $H\,T\,M\,L\,5\,/\,C\,S\,S\,3$ 

Javascript

Nodejs/MongoDB

Responsive design

 $\mathsf{P}\,\mathsf{H}\,\mathsf{P}\,\mathsf{/}\,\mathsf{M}\,\mathsf{y}\,\mathsf{S}\,\mathsf{Q}\,\mathsf{L}$ 

#### OVERVIEW

My expertise lies with building working prototypes and MVP's very quickly and rolling them out in the market for testing and getting the audiences' opinion. My background as a startup co-founder, also gives me enough understanding of how a company works and its risks.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# CTO/Co-founder @ Panelsensor Ltd July 2014 - Present

My responsibilities as a CTO @ Panelsensor, include from managing the developers team and taking critical decisions regarding the application, to building the server infastructure, coding and designing new features.

## Lead Developer @ Speakerzen.me October 2013 - June 2014

After winning the Google Launchpad Athens award, i continued developing the app on the full stack and took responsibilities as a lead developer.

Eventually we stopped developing the application since the startup didn't have the required growth. We did although learn a lot from this "failure".

# Web developer @ Panagiotis Tzellos Individual Company April 2013 - September 2013

I did my internship at Panagiotis Tzellos Company, where i had the task of building multiple application prototypes and testing them on the market to see how they go. It was my first contact with the startup community and i have been a member since then. I used HTML5/CSS3, JS, Phonegap.

# IT support @ TEI of Stereas Elladas January 2012 - December 2012

My main role @ Tei of Stereas Elladas was to maintain the servers and computers across the institution. I learned to handle linux systems at a production state, which was helpful for my later positions where i needed to create such infastructures alone from scratch. I also learnt to use pfSense servers for security purposes and a Windows active directory.

#### EDUCATION

## Bachelor of Applied Science (B.A.Sc.)@TEI Stereas Elladas September 2009 - June 2015

Solid understanding of basic computer science principles. Proficient with human computer interaction, programming and data mining. My thesis was a recommender system algorithm using collaborative filtering.



# Nick Rossolatos

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

|  | D   | ESIGN      |  |   |
|--|-----|------------|--|---|
|  |     | UI/UX      |  |   |
|  |     |            |  |   |
|  | W   | eb Design  |  |   |
|  |     |            |  |   |
|  | Log | o/Branding |  |   |
|  |     |            |  | 1 |

# SOCIAL

"You can find me everywhere"



s p i d e y n r



nickrossolatos



nikosrossolatos

#### LANGUAGES/TOOLS

- HTML5/CSS3, Javascript (3+ years of experience)
- NodeJS/MongoDB (more than 2.5 years of commercial experience)
- PHP/MySQL
- Twitter Bootstrap
- Junior experience with AngularJS/EmberJS
- npm/gulp for task automation
- Browserify
- Github/Bitbucket
- Illustrator (Web Design and Logo Branding)
- Photoshop
- Editor of choice is Sublime Text

| SPEAKING | L A N ( | G U A | 1 G E S |
|----------|---------|-------|---------|
|----------|---------|-------|---------|

GREEK

NATIVE LANGUAGE

ENGLISH

SECOND LANGUAGE

### FACTS

- I own a driver's license
- 3+ years of professional work experience
- Hobbies include: Swimming, Piano, Cycling, Gaming
- I like photography and i am part of a photography group
- · I am a fast learner

### VOLUNTEER

I have been helping other programmers in Greece learn about web development and have been doing some small group meetings, giving assignments and notes on front-end development mostly. The ultimate motive is to help improve the level of Greek digital products and maybe find some good collegues on the way!

Thank you for your time, Nick Rossolatos